Sagar Kar

9085986905(M) | 7002086905 || sagarkar10@gmail.com || sagarkar10.github.io

EDUCATION

NOLOGY. SILCHAR

B.Tech - Computer Sc. & Engg. 2014 - 2018 | CGPA: 8.07

SRIMANTA SHANKAR **CADEMY, GUWAHATI**

HIGHER SECONDARY | SCIENCE 94.2% | Board: CBSE

CERTIFICATES

Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach by University of Washington view Machine Learning by Stanford University

Neural Networks and Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai view Intro to Machine Learning: Google **AWS Machine Learning** Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning

TOOLS

PROGRAMMING

- Python C/C++
- JavaScript R Matlab
- •Octave •SQL •HTML •ETFX

AI/ML LIBRARIES

- •TensorFlow Keras OpenCV
- •Scikit-Learn
- Numpy Pandas Matplotlib NLKT
- •SpaCy •Gensim

FRAMEWORKS

- Jupyter-Notebook Docker
- Kubernetes Mongo DB Lui Gi
- •Git •Airflow

PLATFORM

- Unix/Linux
- AWS (extensively managed and used)
- •GCP •Azure

INTERESTS

- Data-Science Big-Data Deep-Learning
- DevOps Gesture/Image recognition

VOLUNTARY

- •Teaching Assistant, NITS
- Open Source Contributor

SUMMARY

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECH- Self driven and highly motivated data science professional with experience in Machine Learning, Predictive Data Analysis. Exposure to Deep Learning techniques building end-to-end predictive pipelines in Computer Vision and Time Series Analysis. Expert in Unix, experienced in python AI/ML stack for production level contribution. Have exposure to DepOps and Cloud/Distributed Computing.

EXPERIENCE

INSIDER.IN | Machine Learning Engineer

April 2019 - Present | Bangalore, Karnataka

- Dynamic Pricing statistical model to Predict and affect event ticket pricing based on live demand and previous trends.
- Recommendation System for event space having highly volatile items.
- Worked with Named Entity Recognition using NLTK and RNN to extract event details from event banner and posters.

SIGTUPLE | AI ENGINEER

June 2018 - April 2019 | Bangalore, Karnataka

- Microscopic Video analysis and modeling for particle detection and cell tracking using Deep-CNN to report and classify disease with **Human level accuracy**.
- ELT, EDA, and visualization of various medical data for for R&D to recognize, analyse and solve domain-specific or hardware-specific challenges.

NOTIONINK | DNN and AI INTERN

May 2017 - July 2017 | Bangalore, Karnataka

- Worked in Computer Vision developing state-of-art object recognition model for the **AI enabled drone** in C/C++ with support for Python.
- Build D-CNN models for low-end CPU's to replicate bench-mark results and recorded almost 13% more efficiency with code CPU intrinsic optimization using open source Intel-Math Kernel Library and ARM-Compute libraries.
- Implemented Darknet's **YOLO** for ARM's v8 architecture (for x15 and RaspberryPi), with cross platform support for Intel's quad-core.

PRICEBOARD.IN | DATA SCIENCE AND DEVOPS INTERN

May 2016 - July 2016, Dec 2017 | Guwahati, Assam

- Contributed and monitored the open source data manipulation/visualization project AWS-ELK-BILLING (click here) and managed 100 stars in Github.
- Worked on Elastic Search to increase the product search accuracy and also implemented **Collaborative Filtering** for product recommend-er system.
- Build **Product Categorization** method using Neural Network to categorize e-commerce products using NLP techniques on the scrapped data.

PRO JECTS

FREELANCING

- Gamut Analytics | Resume Classification Worked on NLP and Paragraph Segmentation to classify and rank resume based on predefined criteria using MNB, SVM, Decision Trees, and CNN.
- Cheruvu | Soil Analysis and Crop Yield Prediction Worked on Data analysis, Forecasting with ARIMA and ANN to predict soil composition.
- Scribie | Audio Transcript Parser build the parser and sanitizer models using NLP, BRNN, etc which became the base for the training database for auto-transcriber.